時は戦国、乱世の時代。
からくり人の住むジパング国では群雄割拠して合戦に明け暮れ、
からくり武芸者たちも勝利と栄光を目指してしのぎを削っていた。
そしていま、からくり武芸者ナンバー１を目指す、とてつもないヒーローが誕生した！
ムサシ、見参でござるだス！
からくり剣豪伝ムサシロード
男はいつでも　世界の真ん中で
いちばん　強くなる日を
AH! AH! 夢見て
心の刃　大空にふりかざし
冒険の旅の　幕を開ける
ジパング国を　さすらう剣豪
その名　からくりびと　ムサシ
GO! FIGHT!
鍔迫り合いの音が
眩しい人生
戦い　昨日よりも　今日　強い
BUGEI! 二刀流　ムサシ
明日は　輝くぞ
鍔迫り合いの音が
眩しい人生
戦い　思い切りと　静けさと
BUGEI! 二刀流　ムサシ
みけんが　きらめいた　ムサシ！！
참가 등록에 늦어 지팡구 무예 대회에서 쫓겨난 무사시.
Because he was late for the registration, Musashi was expelled from the competition.
제니가탄의 도움으로 대회장 하나에 잠입해서 대활약.
As Zenigatan helped, he infiltrated into the a competition place and showed his skills.
그러나 정체가 밝혀져 관리들에게 쫓겨 사찰의 마루 밑에 도망쳐야 했다.
But his true identity was revealed, and he had to run away and hide under a floor as he was chased by officials.
센히메를 구하고 승부이오
Rescue Senhime
And Have a Match
이 무예 대회는 7개의 대회장에서 먼저 예선이 진행되고 있었다.
In the martial arts competition, preliminary contests were going on in seven places.
천구류, 망아의 검.
Tenguryū, Bouga no Ken.
(lit. Sword of Ecstasy)
제 1 대회장 대표 우시와카 님으로 결정!
The final contestant from the first ground is Ushiwaka!
신선치기!
Shinsengiri!
(lit. Shinsen [family] Slash)
제 2 대회장 대표 콘도 님으로 결정!
The final contestant from the second ground is Kondō!
간류! 츠바메가에시!
Ganryū! Tsubamegaeshi!
제 3 대회장 대표 코지로 님으로 결정!
The final contestant from the third ground is Kojirō!
대장도 고조!
Daichōtō Gojō!
(lit. Big Halberd + place name)
제 4 대회장 대표 벤케이 님으로 결정!
The final contestant from the fourth ground is Benkei!
비검! 제일의 검!
Secret sword! Ichi no Tachi!
(lit. The best longsword)
제 5 대회장 대표, 주베 님으로 결정!
The final contestant from the fifth ground is Jūbee!
쿠사리가마류! 목 베는 낫!
Kusarigamaryū! Kubikarigama!
(lit. Headhunting Sickle)
제 6 대회장 대표, 바이켄 님으로 결정!
The final contestant from the sixth ground is Baiken!
호조인류! 지옥조종반!
Hōzōinryū! Jigoku Kakakuru Ban!
제 7 대회장 대표, 호조인 님으로 결정!
The final contestant from the seventh ground is Hōzōin!
아따! 길을 내쇼! 길을 내시오!
Make way! Make way!
역시 모두 쟁쟁한 사람들만 이겨 왔구만.
Just as expected; only the best people have been winning all the way.
마땅히 여기에 무사시 씨의 이름이 있겠지?
Musashi's name should be here...
어, 저, 무사시를 알고 계십니까?
Excuse me. Do you know Musashi?
아, 조금 폐를 끼쳐서요.
Ah, I've given him some trouble before.
설마 오츠루 씨에 타쿠안 스님이신지?
Could you be Otsuru and the monk Takuan?
맞소.
That's right.
나는 제니가탄이라고 합니다.
I am Zenigatan.
그렇군요. 무사시 씨가 계속 자랑하던 오츠루 씨는 예쁘군.
I see. As Musashi always praised, you sure are pretty, Otsuru.
스님도 들은 대로 꽤나 완고해 보이는군요.
Also, as I heard, you do look stubborn, monk.
-뭐라?
-아니, 다르게 말해서.
-What?
-Nah, it's in my words, not his.
그보다 무사시 씨는 어디에 있나요?
More importantly, where's Musashi?
그게, 내가 묻고 싶은 거야.
That's what I wanted to ask.
관리가 그런 걸 모르면 거...
If the one with a truncheon also has no idea...
이것 참, 어디에 사라졌는지.
Really, where did he disappear to?
이거 맛있소. 맛있소. 참 잘 했소!
This tastes good-dasu! Good job!
다만, 내가 가져오라고 말한 거 아니오. 어디까지나 네가 자신의 의지로 가져온 것이오.
But it's not me who asked you to take these-dasu. These are nothing more than you took by your own free will-dasu.
다음엔 뭔가 마실 거 같은거 원할까나...
Next, I'd like something to drink-dasu...
거참... 요즘 개는 정말 말하는 걸 안 들어서 말이오!
Really... even the dogs nowadays don't listen to what I say-dasu.
숨이 막히오.
The air isn't good here-dasu.
역시 바깥이 제일이오! 상쾌하오!
Outside is the best as always-dasu! How refreshing-dasu!
어쩌고저쩌고 미야모토 마을의 무사시, 이 반역자를 잡아오는 자에게는 10량,
blah blah, this is Musashi from Miyamoto village. We'll reward you 10 ryos if you take him directly.
거처를 알아낸 자에게는 1량의 상금을,
We'll reward you 1 ryo if you find out where he is.
그럼 총 11량!
Then 11 ryos in total!
-그렇게 많이?
-빨리 찾으러 가자!
-That much?
-Let's go get him right away!
이건 정말 어렵소...
This, really I can't do something about-dasu...
-힘내라, 오츠루.
-네.
-Get a grip, Otsuru.
-Right.
왜 내가 반역자가 되어야만 하오!
Why am I even a traitor-dasu?!
겨우 하루 접수가 늦었을 뿐인데.
I was late for the registration only by a day-dasu!
저 영문을 알 수 없는 관리 놈들!
Those blockhead officials!
그래도 배가 고프오... 어라?
But still I'm hungry-dasu... Huh?
하늘은 날 버려도 빨리 오라고 오라고 강이 사랑하나 보오.
Heh, even though the heaven has abandoned me, the river is sending me a love call!
오, 사랑이 왔소, 왔소!
Hey, the love came-dasu! It came-dasu!
밥으로 먹을 거라면 이 녀석을!
I'll take it as my meal!
우와! 뱀장어꼬치이오!
Wow, an eel skewer-dasu!
달아나기 어렵지 않겠어?
Wouldn't it be difficult to run away?
귀여워해 줄게.
We'll take a good care of you.
예쁜 걸 입고 그래.
What a pretty clothes you're putting on.
화난 척 하는 것일까나?
Is she trying to look angry?
그런 걸 휘둘러도 상처를 입을 뿐이지!
Even if you whirl such thing, you'll end up being injured!
일로 넘겨라!
Gimme that!
이 새끼가!
How stupid!
이건 돈이 되겠어!
That would make some money!
누구냐!
Who's that?!
지나가던 자이오.
I'm a passerby-dasu.
왜 손을 밟냐!
Why did you step on my hand?!
사람이 걸어가고 있는데 그쪽이 멋대로 손을 내밀었소.
I was just walking by, and you stick out your hand on your own-dasu.
뭐시라?
What?!
-어, 이놈 무사시다!
-뭐라!?
-Hey, he's Musashi!
-What?
저, 정말이다, 무사시다. 수배자의 인상하고 꼭이야!
Th- that's true! He definitely looks like Musashi!
잡으면 10량이야!
If we get him, they'll award us 10 ryos!
우리가 가져가겠다!
We'll take that!
대단해, 대단해! 무사시는 강하구나!
Awesome, awesome! Aren't you strong, Musashi!?
뭘 그러오. 이런 패거리!
These bunch are nothing!
고마워.
Thank you.
뭔가 묻었소?
Is something on my head-dasu?
아니, 그게 아니라 무예 대회에 나타난 반역자라니까 더 무서운 사람일 거라 생각했는데...
No, that's not it. I thought a traitor appeared in the competition would be a scary person...
의외로 멋진 젊은이잖아!
but aren't you a cool young person! Totally unexpected!
머, 멋지오?
C- cool?
어라?
Huh?
이런 맛있는 것은 태어나서 처음 먹소.
I never had something this tasty-dasu.
부족하면 더 주문할게.
If you need more, I'll order more for you.
그래도 배가 너무 고파서 쓰러지는 건 난 태어나서 처음 봐!
But still, I never saw someone collapsing because of extreme hunger!
꼴불견인 모습을 보이고 말았소.
How unsightly shape I showed to you-dasu!
근데 날 관리에게 날리지 않고 왜 밥을 먹여주시오?
But, why are you offering me food instead of letting the officials know-dasu?
사정을 알고 보면 무사시가 날뛴 것에도 무리가 없어!
Listening to your story, it makes perfect sense that you went wild, Musashi!
나도 화나겠다!
I would get angry too!
알아 주셨다면 감사하오.
Thank you for understanding-dasu.
있잖아, 있잖아!
Hey, hey!
그보다 무사시, 여행하러 가자!
More importantly, Musashi, let's go on a journey!
응, 나하고 같이!
Right, with me!
당신하고?
With you?
나, 정말로 여행가고 싶어서 집을 뛰쳐나왔어.
I wanted to go on a journey, so I ran out from my house!
그러니까 가출?
You've run away from home?
그랬더니 이상한 놈들에게 노려지고!
And then, weird guys were gathering onto me!
가출했다면 돈이 별로 없다는 말...?
If you ran away from your home, does that mean you don't have enough money...?
-응!
-역시...
-Right!
-As expected...
왜 그래, 무사시?
What's wrong, Musashi?
그래도... 돈이 없으면 먹고 달아날 수밖에...
But... if you don't have money, we'll have to run away...
돈 따위 없어도 괜찮아. 그보다 같이 여행으로 가자!
It's alright even without money! More importantly, let's go on a journey!
아니, 가는 거야. 이건 내 명령이에요.
No, you will go. This is my order.
명령? 그래도 나는...
Order? But I'm...
아직 무예 대회에 미련이 있다는 말이에요?
Are you saying that you still have lingering for the martial arts competition?!
아, 그게, 그러니까, 그런 곳에...
Uh, that is... I have...
그럼 내게 좋은 생각이 있어.
Then I have a good idea.
계산은 여기에 받으러 가 줘.
Go to this place for the payment.
괜찮을까...
I wonder if it'll be alright-dasu...
아, 잘 알겠습니다.
Certainly!
기다렸지!
Thank you for waiting!
-화내지 않았소?
-전혀!
-Didn't she get angry-dasu?
-Not at all!
그보다 무사시, 본대회장에 들어가게 해 주면 여행가는 걸로 약속한 거야!
Anyway, Musashi, it's a promise that when I manage to get you into the main competition place, we'll go for a journey!
그렇소.
Right-dasu.
꼭 약속이야!
You will keep that promise!
사내는 두말하지 않소!
A man does not take his words back-dasu!
야호! 최고!
Yay! It's so great!
나, 사내이오.
I am a man-dasu.
7개의 지역 예선장을 합체시키면 결승전을 하는 본대회장이 된다.
When seven separate preliminary contest places combine,
they become the main competition place where the final match will take place in.
나란히, 나란히!
Straight lines please!
네, 네! 네!
Yes, alright! Good!
신체 체크이오!
It's for the body check!
이렇게 엄중한데 어떻게 들어가오?
How can we go through such strict guards?
그러니까 좋은 수가 있댔지!
That's why I told you I have a good idea!
무, 무슨, 무슨 짓이오!
Wh- wha- what're you doing-dasu?!
서두르지 마. 벗는 건 여기까지.
Don't be misled. I'm not taking all my clothes off.
자, 그걸 잘 뒤집어써.
Now, cover yourself well with that.
어떤 일이 있어도 얼굴을 보이면 안 돼.
No matter what, you must not show your face.
곱게 자란 영애로 만들어 줄 거야.
I'll make you a gentle esteemed daughter.
뭣이오, 곱게 자란 영애라니...
What is a gentle esteemed daughter-dasu?
어쨌든 정숙한 여성처럼!
Anyway act like a graceful lady!
입장권을 보이시오.
Show your ticket.
근데 이 분은...?
Who is this person here?
미야코 궁전을 떠나는 영애로 꼭 무예 대회를 보고 싶다고 해서 데려왔다.
She's a daughter of a noble, soon to leave Miyako Palace.
I've brought her with me, as she wanted to watch the competition so much.
무례하다! 네 이름을 대, 대, 대, 대, 대, 대!
That's impolite! Tell me your name, name, name, name, name, name!
예, 예! 면목없습니다!
Yes, understood! We're very sorry!
-그럼 지나간다.
-예! 지나가십시오!
-Then, we shall go ahead.
-Right! Go ahead!
가자, 무사토 공주.
Let's go, Princess Musato.
실례하오.
Excuse me-dasu.
대체 이 아가씨는 누구인가? 질풍노도의 후반을 기다려라!
Who is this girl? Wait for the stormy latter half!
약속대로 본 대회장에 들어왔어.
We're in the main competition site, as promised.
고맙소.
Thank you-dasu.
이번엔 네가 약속한 걸 지킬 차례야.
Now it's your turn to keep the promise.
알고 있소. 우와, 대단하오! 주베 씨도 콘도도 대부분 막상막하이오!
I know-dasu. Wow, that's awesome! Jūbee, Kondō, and everyone are so skilled!
무사시!
Musashi!
아야야야야, 이오.
Ouch... -dasu.
뭐야, 얘?
Who's this?
누, 누구냐!
Wh- who's this?!
무사시 님.
Musashi.
아, 주베 씨!
Ah, Jūbee!
우와, 모두!
Hey, everyone!
저 자가 대회를 어지럽히는 반역자로 수배중인 미야모토 마을의 무사시입니다.
He is Musashi from Miyamoto village, the one making a mess in the competition, wanted as a traitor.
뭐, 뭐라?
Wh- what?!
무사시! 어떤 일이 있었던간에 반역자는 절대 용서할 수 없다! 각오해라!
Musashi! No matter what happened, being a traitor is unforgivable! Prepare yourself!
아, 아니오! 잠, 잠깐 기다리시오!
N- no! Wait! Please wait-dasu!
변명은 필요없다!
No need for excuse!
무사시!
Musashi!
어쩔 수 없소!
You're making me do this-dasu!
꽤나 하는군, 무사시.
You're pretty good, Musashi.
무사시 님. 훌륭하오.
Musashi. That was splendid.
주베 씨, 오랜만이오!
It's been a while, Jūbee-dasu!
무사시 님. 왜 이런 짓을 하십니까?
Musashi. Why are you doing this?
왜 정직하게 무예 대회에 출전하지 않으셨습니까?
Why didn't you participate in the competition in a honest way?
미안하오...
I'm sorry-dasu.
나, 신청을 아슬아슬하게 못 해서...
I was a little bit late for the registration-dasu...
저런.
Is that so?
무사시 님 스럽군요.
That's totally you, Musashi.
이야! 부끄럽소.
I'm embarrassed-dasu!
반역자에게 박수를 하다니 무슨 짓이냐!
What are you doing, to clap for a traitor?!
잡아라! 무사시인가 하는 놈, 잡아라!
Get him! Get that Musashi guy!
짐을 거스르는 자라면 설마 어린이라 해도 용서할 수 없다!
Whoever defies me is unforgivable, even if it's a child!
기다려 주십시오, 쇼군!
Please wait, shōgun!
뭐라?
What?
저 자가 쇼군 이에야스...
He must be the shōgun Ieyasu...
뭔가, 주베.
What is it, Jūbee?
이 무사시,
This Musashi.
악의가 있어서 대회에서 난리를 피운 것이 아닙니다.
He did not disturbed the competition with a bad intention.
단지 간발의 차로 마감을 못 맞추었기 때문에...
He was simply a little bit late for the registration.
이유야 어떻든 폐를 끼친 것은 분명하다.
Whatever the reason is, he did make a trouble.
용서할 수 없다!
Unforgivable!
그럼 이 주베와 번외 시합을 하게 해 주십시오!
Then please let him have an extra match against me, Jūbee!
뭐라?
What?
그렇게 하면...
By doing so...
무사시도 만족할 것입니다.
Musashi should be satisfied.
우와, 만족하오! 만족하오! 주베 씨하고 하면 만족이오!
Wow, I'll be satisfied, definitely satisfied! I'll be satisfied if I can have a match with Jūbee-dasu!
쇼군. 저도 부탁드립니다.
Shōgun, I also ask you for that.
마찬가지입니다, 쇼군!
Same for me, Shōgun!
-저도 부탁드리오!
-저도 부탁드립니다.
-I ask for your favor!
-I also ask you to do so.
나도다!
Me too!
어쩔 수 없지. 그럼 저도 부탁드립니다!
Inevitable. Then I'll ask for that too!
모두...
Everyone...
쇼군!
Shōgun!
음, 흥미롭군. 볼 가치 있는 승부가 될 것인가?
Interesting. Will it be a match worth seeing?
보장해드립니다.
I guarantee that.
좋다. 특별히 허가하지.
Alright. I will allow this as an exception.
아싸!
Yay!
분에 넘치는 기쁨입니다.
I am very happy to hear that.
지금부터 번외 시합.
An extra match will begin now.
주베 님 대 무사시 님, 단판 승부!
Jūbee vs Musashi. One-game match!
시작!
Start!
대단하군, 주베.
Excellent job, Jūbee.
이건 확실히 흥미롭구나.
This definitely is interesting.
저런, 이곳저곳 안내도 받고.
Thanks for guiding us to various places.
덕분에 에도토피아 구경을 할 수 있었소이다.
That was a great Edotopia sightseeing.
별 말씀을. 무사시 씨를 찾는 김이니까.
It's nothing. We were finding Musashi anyway.
오늘부터 결승전이 시작한다 했으니...
So I heard that the final match starts today...
각 예선 대회장이 하나가 된 본 대회장이지요.
The main competition place is formed by combining each preliminary places.
그래도... 무사시 씨가 나오지 않은 무예 대회 따위...
But... it's a martial arts competition without Musashi...
그래.
That's right.
봐도 시시하구나.
It'll be boring.
이쪽도 사실은 경비의 일이 있으니 왠지 맥이 빠지는군요.
It somewhat lost its flavor, as I have a guard job.
무사시 씨는 대체 어디에 가 버렸을지...
I wonder where did Musashi disappear to...
대단해!
Awesome!
무사시!
Musashi!
안 돼! 이대로는 당하오! 이대로는!
No! I'll be done for at this rate-dasu! I need something!
어떻게 타개할 방법은 없소?
Is there a way to get over-dasu?
비검! 제일의 검!
Secret sword! Ichi no Tachi!
승부 났습니다! 주베 님의 승리!
Match set! Jūbee wins!
훌륭했다.
That was excellent.
졌소...
I lost...
나는 주베 씨에게 졌소...
I lost to Jūbee...
뭣이오?
Wh- what is this-dasu?
오랜만이다, 무사시. 아니, 반역자.
It's been a while, Musashi. No, traitor.
한조!
Hanzō!
이 줄을 푸시오!
Untie this thread-dasu!
상황 파악 못하는 놈.
You're one guy without common sense.
무사시!
Musashi!
이걸로 무사시의 사형은 확정이군.
Musashi's death penalty is set by this.
사, 사형?!
De- death penalty?
그렇다.
Indeed.
반역자 주제에 또 뻔뻔하게 본대회장에 몰래 들어가고 날뛰었다.
You've crept inside the main competition place and acted violently without shame, making you a traitor.
날뛰었다?
Acted violently?
그건 주베 씨가 번외 시합을!
Jūbee asked for an extra match...
닥쳐라!
Shut up!
방금 막 자신의 죄를 인정하는 인감을 한 참이 아닌가!
You have just acknowledged your offense by signing on this!
뭣이오?
What?
나 무사시는 자신이 저지른 죄를 인정하고 사형에 처해져도 어쩔 수 없습니다.
I, Musashi, acknowledge the crime I committed myself and agree to be executed no matter what.
뭣이오, 이건? 이런 건 난 모르오!
What is this-dasu?! I don't know about this-dasu!
젠장...
Damn...
꾸미고 있었소, 한조!
It was all your plan-dasu, Hanzō!
미야모토 마을의 무사시.
Musashi from Miyamoto village.
드디어 저 세상으로 매장해 버릴 때가 온 것인가.
The time to bury to the afterworld has finally come.
불쌍한 무사시. 한조의 마의 손에 떨어져 그 젊은 삶을 끝내게 되는가.
How pitiful is Musashi. Will his youthful life will come to an end in Hanzō's hands?
지팡구 무예 대회에서 우승하는 것을 꿈꾼 젊은이가
A young man who just wanted to be a champion in Jipangu Martial Arts Competition is
그 꿈을 이루지 못하고 바야흐로 처형되려 하고 있다.
about to be executed without being able to make that dream come true.
이 무사시를 구할 자, 과연 있을까, 없을까?
Will there be anyone who'll save this Musashi, or not?
カラのポケットに　ツキが
飛び込むことも　あるさ
おっきな声で　笑えば
あしたには　朝が来る
無くすものなんか　何もないさ
やっちゃえ！イケイケ！
手ぶらは　強いぜ
てなもんだ　のーてんきに行こう
人生　てなもんさ　チャンスが　ほら
しっぽを振って　追ってくるぜ
てなもんだ　のーてんきに行こう
未来も　てなもんさ　あしたが　ほら
両手ひろげて　笑ってるぜ
무예 대회도 슬슬 끝나 가오.
The martial arts competition is about to end.
이게 무슨, 결승전은 코지로와 주베 씨.
No way! The final match is Kojirō vs Jūbee.
왜 내가 아닌 것이오! 분하오!
Why isn't it me? How frustrating!
분하고 있을 때가 아니오! 나, 한조에게 사형당하려는 틈이오.
This is no time to be frustrated-dasu! I'm about to be executed by Hanzō-dasu.
지팡구 제일의 무예가가 될 생각을 할 때가 아니오!
It's no time to become the number one martial artist of Jipangu!
누가 도와주시오!
Somebody help me!
다음 이야기! 카라쿠리 검호 총출격!
Next story! Karakuri Martial Artists, Go Out at Once-dasu!
질풍노도의 대역전을 보시오!
Watch the stormy twist-dasu!
다음 이야기
카라쿠리 검호 총출격
기대하세요!
Next Episode
Karakuri Martial Artists
Go Out at Once!
Look forwards for it!